MISSION 75 "IT'S JUST WHITE DAY."
（任務75 是白色情人節）
H-Here… I-It's friend chocolate.
這個…是友情巧克力
Tadano replayed Valentine's Day in his head a hundred times a day.
情人節當天的情景 一天會在腦中浮現100次的只野同學
POOF
（漲紅）
-MARCH 8 -It's already March.
-（3月8日） -已經3月了
I have to think about White Day gifts.
該想想白色情人節的回禮該送什麼了
THE WRAPPER FROM KOMI'S CHOCOLATE
（從古見同學那收到的巧克力包裝）
SNIFF
（聞）
I-It's not what you think!
妳別誤會了喔！
Huh? What is?
什麼？誤會什麼？
But what should I give in return?
但我該送什麼回禮才好？
I hear about candies and marshmallows…
雖然常聽到別人會 回送糖果或棉花糖…
Wow, they have meanings.
是喔，原來還有各自代表的意義啊
Candies mean "like." But marshmallows mean "hate."
送糖果代表“喜歡” 棉花糖則是“討厭”
Cookies mean "friends."
餅乾則是“朋友”啊
This just made it worse.
反而更讓人煩惱了
Should I ask Hitomi?
要跟瞳商量看看嗎？
Yeah, but… no…
不過這樣好嗎？但是…
You're distracting!
你這樣我很難專心耶！
I was just thinking about a good return gift for White Day.
老實說我在煩惱白色情人節的回禮
White Day?
白色情人節？
A return gift for your male friend?
是從男性朋友收到的那個嗎？
Uh… yeah!
對，沒錯！
That's it!
就是那個！
What?
突然間怎麼了啊？
If it's a return gift for chocolate from a boy,
如果是要回送男性朋友的
wouldn't food be alright?
那買吃的就好了吧？
Or you could give chocolate back.
回送巧克力也行
I was thinking of something a little more substantial…
我想說也許可以準備 稍微正式一點的回禮…
-You're in love? -WITH THAT BOY
-你喜歡他嗎？ -（那個男生）
N-No!
才沒有！
Based on his reaction…
根據哥哥這個反應…
And the shadow on that day…
還有那天的人影…
About 165 centimeters tall, long-haired silhouette,
身高大約165公分，長髮的身影
and the faint footsteps I heard were close together!
當天隱約有聽到 間隔很短的腳步聲！
My brother…
哥哥…
got some chocolate!
一定是收到巧克力了！
W-What's that?
幹嘛啦？
Fine then. I'll help you think of something.
真拿你沒辦法，我就認真幫你想吧
NO CUSHION FOR ME…
（沒有我的坐墊啊）
First, was it friend chocolate?
首先，你收到的是友情巧克力？
Or real love chocolate?
還是真愛巧克力？
Um, friend chocolate. I think.
這個嘛，我猜應該是友情巧克力
You think?
你猜是友情巧克力？
That's what I was… told.
對方是這麼說的
It might not be true, though.
所以也可能是要隱藏自己的害羞囉？
I guess…
可能吧…
I mean, no!
不！
I-I don't think that's it.
我想不是那樣啦
If it's true love chocolate, a gift that lasts would be nice.
真愛巧克力的回禮 收到能保留形體的東西應該比較開心
-I see. -You like this person?
-原來如此 -你喜歡那個人嗎？
I already said no!
就說不是那樣！
Hang on! Choose between "like" or "hate."
等等！是“喜歡”還是“討厭”？
Hm? Oh, in that case…
什麼？硬要說的話…
This is about Katai, right?
她是在說片居同學吧？
"Like" I guess… so what?
算是“喜歡”吧，那又怎樣？
-Ugh! That's not what I mean! -What are you talking about?!
-真是的！我不是在說這個！ -妳到底在說什麼？
Whoa.
哇
Imagine this person clearly in your head.
你好好在腦中想著對方的事
Listen.
哥哥你…
Do you like them?
喜歡她嗎？
I suppose… I do have feelings.
我想是有點在意啦
-Huh? -SO CUTE.
-什麼？ -（真可愛）
Why are you mad?
她為什麼要發怒啊？
I understand the situation.
情況我瞭解了
To the department store!
我們要去百貨公司囉！
H-Hitomi?
瞳小姐？
I saw it on The Noon Show.
在《已是中午了》介紹過的
Snacks that look good on social media!
社群媒體打卡 上相甜點我也已經調查好了喔！
Hitomi!
瞳小姐！
But listen.
但哥哥你聽好囉
Anything is okay from someone you like!
只要是喜歡的人送的 不管收到什麼禮物都好
Don't you think so?
你不這麼覺得嗎？
Hitomi!
瞳小姐！
MOM ONLY KNOWS ABOUT THE CHOCOLATE FROM A BOY.
（只野同學的媽媽只知道 他有收到男生送的巧克力）
March 13, Friday.
3月13日，星期五
White Day falls on a Saturday, not a school day.
白色情人節是星期六，不用去學校
The boys who got chocolate are nervous.
因此收到巧克力的男生們都躁動不安
The girls have already finished their duties.
相反地因為該做的都已經做了
They're calm and collected.
女生們都很冷靜
The boys who didn't get any chocolate have reached enlightenment.
而沒有收到巧克力的 男生們也都早已看開
Komi!
古見同學！
Here's your White Day return gi--
這是白色情人節的回…
Komi! Here's your White Day return gift!
古見同學！這是白色情人節的回禮！
-CANDY SCULPTURE -Go on and lick your favorite part of me!
-（糖人） -妳喜歡我的哪個部分都可以舔喔！
T-Thanks!
謝謝你！
-HEART RACING -Anxiety.
-（心跳加速） -心神疲累
N-Next is the return gift for my mentor!
下一個回禮對象是師父！
OMINOUS
（來勢洶洶）
-Muscle mass is all I can offer my mentor… -HOW TO ATTAIN BEAUTIFUL MUSCLES
-我贏得過師父的也只有肌肉量了… -（《鍛鍊出美麗的肌肉》）
D-Does she like it?
她會喜歡我的回禮嗎？
And then there's Tadano.
接著，說到只野同學…
Oh yeah!
啊，對了！
Want to eat something after school today? My treat.
今天放學後要不要一起吃飯？我請客
-Katai. -BEEF BOWL?
-片居同學 -（牛肉蓋飯？）
He faltered!
他臨陣退縮了！
A result of being too nervous to give Komi her gift.
因為要送回禮給古見同學太緊張了
He told himself, "T-Today's an unlucky day."
他開始在腦中想著 “反正今天是大凶日”
In the end he couldn't do it.
結果只野同學的回禮就這樣送不出去
Huh? A date?
什麼？是約會嗎？
That's a date, isn't it?!
那是約會對吧？
And so Friday the 13th passed uneventfully.
結果13號的星期五 什麼都沒發生，就這樣結束了
-MARCH 14, SATURDAY -White Day.
-（3月14日星期六） -白色情人節當天
While everyone else was giving out gifts,
在大家都順利送出回禮時
Tadano had faltered.
臨陣退縮的只野同學
Now he had no other choice but to go to Komi's and hand it over.
只能親自去古見同學家送出回禮
-Don't stay out too late! -SMIRK
-別太晚回來喔！ -（奸笑）
See ya.
我出門了
I never thought I'd be this nervous.
我從沒想過會這麼緊張
I came to her house.
我還特地跑到她家來
I… I hope she doesn't take it the wrong way.
應該不會讓她產生 什麼不必要的誤會吧
No, I'll just hand it over at the door.
但我只是要在玄關交給她而已
It'll be fine…
應該沒問題吧…
It might not be fine.
也可能會出問題呢
-Suspicious? -UNSTABLE
-是可疑人士？ -（情緒不穩）
But…
但是…
I guess she was…
比起我，她那時…
even more nervous than this.
應該更緊張吧？
-TADANO IS FALTERING -I pushed it! I want to run away!
-（立刻就退縮的只野同學） -按下去了！好想逃走！
Yes?
請問是哪位？
S-Someone answered!
有人回覆了！
-MALE VOICE… HER YOUNGER BROTHER? -Um, is Komi…
-（是男生的聲音，她弟弟嗎？） -那個，古見同學…
Uh, is S-Shoko there?
啊，請問硝子同學在嗎？
I-I'm a friend from school.
我是她學校的朋友
I-It's uh, Tadano.
敝姓只野
-BEEP -He hung up?!
-（掛斷） -他掛斷了？
-W-What's wrong, Tadano? -MOTHER
-怎麼了嗎？只野同學 -（媽媽）
-Hello. Is Shoko home? -TADANO RESPONDED NORMALLY.
-妳好，硝子同學在嗎？ -（冷靜回覆的只野同學）
Shoko is out on an errand.
我請硝子出門幫我辦事了
Sorry for the bad timing.
抱歉，時機不太好
Oh, uh, I'll come back later…
什麼？這樣啊，那我晚點再…
Come in and wait!
你進來等吧！
-Come in and wait! -Uh… Um…
-你進來等吧！ -不，那個…
I'll bring some tea. Make yourself at home.
我端茶過來，把這當成自己家吧
Oh, thanks. Don't mind me.
不好意思，不用這麼麻煩啦
-What should I do? -SQUIRM
-我該做些什麼？ -（坐立難安）
Oh, sor…
啊，不好意…
Her father?
是她的爸爸？
T-Thank you.
謝謝
-SITTING -He's sitting?!
-（就坐） -他要坐下嗎？
W-What?
怎麼回事？
-SIP -Oh, he's drinking it.
-（啜飲） -那杯是他要喝的啊
-COULDN'T HANDLE THE SILENCE -M-My name is Hitohito Tadano.
-（受不了沉默而開始講話） -我叫只野仁人
I'm Ko… ah, Sho…
我跟古…我跟硝…
I'm in your daughter's class, and I study hard every day!
跟令嬡在同一個班級，每天專心讀書
And, uh.
然後…
She gave me some friend chocolate for Valentine's Day.
因為在情人節收到了 令嬡贈與的友情巧克力
So I came to give a return gi…
今天特此前來…
Sir!
回禮！
BANG
（打開）
PUSH
（用力推）
TADANO IS FLUSTERED
（跟著不知所措的只野同學）
OPEN CLOSET, SCATTERED BOOKS CAST-OFF CLOTHES, MESSY BLANKET
（開一半的衣櫃，沒收好的書 散亂的衣服，亂糟糟的棉被）
-BAM BOOM SLAM CRUNCH -I-It's not that messy!
-（奔跑，關上，整理） -房間並沒有那麼亂喔！
WHEW
（喘氣）
SLOWS HER BREATH
（調整呼吸的古見同學）
TADANO WATCHES AND WAITS
（觀察對方的只野同學）
KOMI CALMS DOWN
（冷靜下來的古見同學）
ADJUSTS HIS POSTURE
（再次坐正的只野同學）
HASN'T CALMED DOWN
（果然還是很慌張的古見同學）
TADANO DRINKS DAD'S TEA
（跟古見同學的爸爸 喝同一杯茶的只野同學）
TADANO CAN'T FIND A WAY TO START
（不知道怎麼開口的只野同學）
KOMI KNOWS TODAY IS WHITE DAY.
（清楚知道今天是 白色情人節的古見同學）
Uh.
那個…
Oh. No. Sorry.
啊，不好意思
This is, uh, thank you for the Valentines' gift.
請收下這個 謝謝妳在情人節送的禮物
H-Here's the return gift.
這是巧克力的回禮
Go ahead. Look inside.
請打開看看
HAND CREAM
（護手霜）
CUTE!
（好可愛！）
It's not quite the right season anymore.
雖然現在的季節可能不太適合用
But I found one with a nice smell, so I chose it.
但我找到味道很香的，就選了那個
-I hope you like it. -BOW
-如果妳喜歡的話就太好了 -（點頭致意）
That's uh… a candy.
那個是糖果
W-Well, I'll get going!
那我差不多要回去了！
I don't want to disturb your day off.
難得的放假日我也不便久待
Can't have that!
不然會打擾到妳！
NOD
（點頭）
IT SMELLED GOOD.
（味道很香）
-Sato, hold this! -Sure!
-左藤，妳拿這個！ -好啊！
Komi.
古見同學
Is this rag alright for wiping desks?
這條抹布是可以用來擦桌子的嗎？
Komi?
古見同學？
Die!
受死吧！
ROLL
（滾）
-Let's play Eraser Drop! -ERASER DROP
-來玩橡皮擦擂臺吧！ -（橡皮擦擂臺）
Huh? Why?
什麼？為什麼？
Eraser Drop.
“橡皮擦擂臺”
The history of humanity.
集結人類歷史中
All its wisdom was concentrated in creating this object, the eraser.
所有智慧而創造出來的產物，橡皮擦
-By the hand of man, it was created… -The last eraser on the desk wins!
-透過人類的手，進而體現… -總之用橡皮擦把對方的打落就贏了
-My time to shine. -YADANO, 10 YEARS
-該我出場了 -（矢田野真華留，十年資歷）
The battlefield for the tournament is…
決鬥的戰場就在
Tadano's desk.
只野同學的桌子上
Set!
預備！
Round one.
第一回合
SPEED STAR NZ3, MAKERU ERASER, KOMI'S ERASER, ZAFU II
（紮夫二，疾星 古見的，真華留改）
-Fight! -BEAM
-開打！ -（閃亮）
First and best!
先下手為強！
-Whoa! -GRIND
-天啊！ -（扭壓）
She's sticking her eraser down with kneaded eraser!
她很用力地壓橡皮擦 讓軟橡皮擦黏在桌子上！
-It's the "Barricade!" -GRIND
-這招是“鐵壁”！ -（扭壓）
BARRICADE: STICKING THE ERASER TO THE DESK.
（鐵壁，將橡皮擦黏在桌上的戰術）
Komi, you can go first.
古見同學可以先開始喔
PLINK
（微微滾動）
Ox walk.
“牛步”
-Komi's biding her time? -OX WALK - BARELY MOVING THE ERASER
-是故意不動來引誘對方失誤嗎？ -（牛步，幾乎不移動的招數）
-She's using a good strategy! -SHE JUST MISSED IT
-古見選手挑了適合擦布的好戰術！ -（只是單純失手）
WHO ARE YOU TALKING TO?
（你在跟誰說話？）
Alright, my turn.
那換我囉
Die!
受死吧！
NAJIMI OSANA DISQUALIFIED
（出界 長名馴染喪失資格）
I'm up next.
接著換我了
UNGH!
看我的！
She ruined her barricade setup and sent it flying!
竟然把難得做出來的 鐵壁橡皮擦彈飛了！
Why?!
為什麼啊？
OUT OF BOUNDS YADANO MAKERU DISQUALIFIED
（出界 矢田野真華留喪失資格）
Next is Tadano.
下一個換只野同學了
-ZAFU II -KOMI'S ERASER
（紮夫二 古見同學的橡皮擦）
WAH!
看招！
WHOOSH!
（飛越）
THUNK
（撞）
-Hitohito Tadano, disqualified. -EXCITED
-只野仁人，喪失資格 -（不知為何情緒高昂）
Komi wins by elimination.
比賽結果，古見同學獲勝
Alright, next game!
好，下一場遊戲！
The time has come.
時機已到
-I know you want to see my power. -NAKANAKA 4 YEARS EXPERIENCE
-你們很想見識我的力量吧 -（中中思春，四年資歷）
New challenger, Nakanaka!
新挑戰者，中中！
-Don't worry, Komi! -You!
-請放心，古見同學！ -妳這傢伙是…
New challenger, Yamai.
-新挑戰者，山井！ -我死也會死守古見同學的橡皮擦
That's like saying your headache hurts.
妳的語意重複了 就跟“我頭痛好痛”一樣
-Huh? -Ah?
-妳說什麼？ -怎樣？
The phoenix Najimi rises again!
我就是不死鳥馴染！
Round two.
第二回合
Fight!
開打！
Oh my.
哎呀
What's this?
怎麼回事啊？
Eraser Drop! I want to play too!
是橡皮擦擂臺！我也想玩！
Huh? Wasn't this a turn battle type of game?
什麼？不是我知道的玩法耶 那應該是回合制戰鬥吧？
Me too!
我也想玩！
We're reserving the third match.
第三回合就由我們預約囉
Everyone's too excited to play Eraser Drop!
大家也太想玩這個遊戲了吧
This will be a fierce battle to end all Eraser Drop battles!
完全超越了過去的 橡皮擦擂臺，展現出精彩的攻防！
It has already blown away the concept of a turn battle!
這已經顛覆了回合制戰鬥的概念！
Is that allowed?
那樣好嗎？
Okay!
注意！
Third battle for the second round at this desk!
第二回合的第三戰在這張桌子比！
Consolation match over here!
敗部復活戰在這裡比喔！
A tournament?
是大賽？
I don't know how I wound up playing.
不知不覺就已經參賽了
What should I do?!
怎麼辦啦？
I've never played Eraser Drop before!
我從來沒玩過橡皮擦擂臺！
And why the crowd?
再說為什麼有這麼多人啦？
NOD
（點頭）
I'll show you a real eraser battle.
就讓你見識一下真正的橡皮擦大戰
It's okay.
別放在心上
Hey! That stage!
喂！看那邊的戰場！
Nakanaka is tired!
中中已經累了！
She exhausted her finger!
手指已經使用過度了！
Weak constitution!
她是虛弱體質！
What's that?
那個是什麼？
Using a finger reinforcement device!
那傢伙竟然強化了手指的力量！
That's cheating! You're a cheater, Najimi!
卑鄙！太卑鄙了，馴染！
Winning is all that matters!
只要能獲勝就好！
Now! Komi's…
就是現在！古見同學的…
FLICK
（彈）
…single shot!
致勝的一擊！
WOOO!
（歡呼）
-Right here… -Yeah! You can do it!
-是這邊嗎？ -可以！
-Wow! -Yes.
-好強喔！ -太棒了
I knew it.
果然沒錯
Uh, ah, i-is it my turn?
換我了嗎？
That was not okay.
就說那樣不行！
What should I do?
該怎麼辦呢？
Yay!
好耶！
Yay! Third battle!
好耶！晉級第三回合！
Don't worry about it!
別太在意！
It's a comeback!
我復活了！
-I'm next! -No, me!
-下個換我！ -是我啦！
-Me! -It is I!
-是我吧！ -我啦！
Oh, right. Komi, you've got a second ma…
話說回來古見同學接著是第二回合…
Komi?
古見同學？
Are you alright? Do you feel sick?
妳還好嗎？身體不舒服嗎？
SORRY. IT'S OKAY. I'M FINE.
（不好意思，沒事，我很好）
I see.
這樣啊
Hey, Tadano.
那麼只野同學
-I have something to do! Bye! -WHAT ABOUT STUDENT COUNCIL?
-我還有其他事，先走了！ -（班級幹部會議就交給你了）
Hey!
你這傢伙！
My ally. Let us meet in battle another day.
我的盟友啊，我們改日再戰了
G-Good work again today!
今天也辛苦了！
-Bye-bye Komi! -Kiss me goodbye!
-拜拜囉，古見同學！ -跟我吻別嘛！
WHACK
（重擊）
-Bye! Take care! -TODAY I WILL GREET KOMI.
-那就這樣囉，回家路上小心！ -（今天一定要跟古見大人打招呼）
It's raining, huh.
下起雨了呢
Do you have an umbrella?
妳有帶傘嗎？
I HAVE A FOLDING UMBRELLA.
（我有折疊傘）
Oh, good.
這樣啊，太好了
I brought one too.
我也有帶傘來
I'm… sad.
我覺得很寂寞
There are only a few days…
再過幾天
until the end of year assembly.
就是結業式了
A little… over a week.
只剩一個多星期
A-And we'll start with new classes.
就會換到新的班級
This time will end.
想到這段時間將要結束
And I'm sad.
就讓人感到寂寞
I understand.
我懂
This year has gone by so fast.
仔細想想，今年轉眼間就過了呢
At first, you made friends with Najimi.
一開始妳跟馴染變成朋友
Najimi says some pretty wild things,
他講出來的話雖然很無厘頭
but thanks to them, everyone got closer.
但我想就是因為有他在 大家的感情才會這麼好
They're pretty relentless.
他總是積極地拉大家一把
And then you made friends with Agari.
之後妳跟上理同學變成朋友
Agari really surprised us when we went to eat with her.
跟她吃飯的時候真的被嚇到了
We should go out to eat together again.
希望我們以後還能一起去吃飯
Yamai and Nakanaka are like cats and dogs,
山井同學跟中中同學看起來水火不容
but I think they make a good pair.
但我覺得她們其實意外地合得來
Onemine and Otori are both so reliable.
尾根峰同學跟尾雞同學很沉穩
They feel so safe.
很讓人放心
Like they can take care of things.
讓人覺得可以放心交給她們
On the field trip,
校外教學的時候
you got to know Kato and Sasaki.
妳能跟加藤同學和佐佐木同學 變得要好，真是太好了
I was glad about that, too.
我也覺得很開心
Sato's morning cleaning.
左藤同學早上的打掃工作
It's too bad we could only help towards the end.
只有在最後才幫到一點忙，很可惜呢
She's been doing it all along and I feel guilty.
一直都是她負責打掃，總覺得很抱歉
It would be nice to hang out with Maeda and Ushiroda, too.
也很想跟前田同學 還有牛路田同學一起出去玩呢
Sports Day, the Culture Festival…
運動會、文化祭
going shopping, going to the pool.
去購物、去游泳池
Going to the festival…
也去了廟會…
the Christmas party, the snowball fight, visiting the shrine, and buying fortunes.
還有聖誕派對、打雪仗 新年參拜時還抽了籤對吧？
The rain isn't stopping.
雨下個不停呢
But it will stop sometime.
但是總有一天會放晴的
It's like…
那個…
comparing the rainstorm while trying to say something profound…
本來想講一些 關於雨過天晴的話來鼓勵妳
but it was harder than I thought.
結果比我想得要難
Silly me.
這下頭大了
Silly you.
確實是呢
-BANG! -I forgot my eraser!
-（打開！） -我忘記拿橡皮擦了！
THUMP
（心跳加速）
Huh? You two haven't left yet?
你們兩個還沒回去啊？
Let's go together! Let me in your umbrella.
那我們一起回家吧！跟我共撐一把傘
Didn't you have something to do?
你不是有其他事要辦嗎？
HM?
什麼？
-Don't give me that. -YOU JUST WANTED TO LEAVE EARLY…
-居然給我來這招 -（你只是想早點回去啊）
Do you want to invite everyone out after the last day of school?
對了，結業式當天約大家一起去玩吧
Yeah!
好主意！
Okay, Komi. You invite everyone!
那麼古見同學，妳負責去邀其他人！
NOD
（點頭）
D-Don't push yourself too hard!
不用太勉強喔！
NUMBER 6 FEBRUARY TO MARCH
（《第六本，2月到3月》）
NUMBER 7 APRIL
（《第七本，4月》）
SECOND YEAR STUDENTS
（二年級生）
Good morning, Komi.
早安，古見同學
GOOD MORNING
（早安）
I…
接…
I hope we…
接下來的一年
can… have another…
也要請你…
good year.
多多指教
WHEN A PERSON HAS EXTREME SOCIAL ANXIETY, THEY STRUGGLE TO COMMUNICATE WITH OTHERS.
（交流障礙症者不擅與人交流）
BEAR IN MIND, THEY ONLY STRUGGLE TO FORM CONNECTIONS.
（但這些人只是不擅長社交）
IT DOESN'T MEAN THEY DON'T WANT TO.
（不表示他們不想和別人有往來）
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻譯：黃思為